# **ALAN AVERY**

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Enthusiastic programmer with more than 10 years' experience leading creative teams. Now excited to marry a background in design with an affinity for organized, technical thinking, and produce inspired software that perfectly balances form and function.

# **SKILLS**

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, PHP

Libraries and Frameworks: React, AngularJS, jQuery, Node.js, Express,

Ruby on Rails

Database Technology: SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Github, command-line interface

**Programming Competencies:** computer science fundamentals, algorithms, information architecture, mobile-centric responsive design, MVC pattern, APIs, code organization and readability, version control, automated testing, error handling

Web Design: Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign

# WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY CHICAGO, IL

Software Engineering Immersive Student, 10/2020-01/2021

- Completed a 12-week, 500-hour full stack program, providing experience
  with current front and back end programming languages, tools and
  methodologies, including web architecture, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API's,
  Node.js, Express, databases, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Python and Ruby.
- Assembled a portfolio of individually and collaboratively-created web applications, including:
  - A digital version of the game "Guess Who?", in which users play against the computer, asking it questions in an attempt to guess its "Mystery Person". Built using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
  - A trip-planning web app that allows users to quickly throw an itinerary together, rearrange it with ease, then save it to a database for future use. Built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express and PostgreSQL.

#### CONTACT

Location: Chicago, IL Phone: 260-580-2216

Email: AlanRAvery@gmail.com

Portfolio: mravery.com

GitHub: github.com/delayedaa

# **WORK HISTORY**

## GREAT WOLF RESORTS CHICAGO, IL

## Creative Services Manager, 05/2018-06/2020

- Overhauled the internal creative team, following a corporate relocation to Chicago. Related tasks included hiring new talent, acquiring reputable vendors and establishing processes for successful project management.
- Guided designers, project managers and freelance creatives in developing marketing and operational materials for each of the company's 19 resorts.

#### AISLE ROCKET STUDIOS CHICAGO, IL

#### Associate Creative Director, 11/2017-03/2018

- Supervised a team of art directors and copywriters spread across 3 cities, boosting interoffice verbal communication and problem solving.
- Revived appliance brand Jenn-Air with a suite of updated customer communications, all of which were recreated to improve the customer experience and align with current brand guidelines.

#### CONVERSANT CHICAGO. IL

#### Lead Senior Art Director, 08/2017-10/2017

- Established new brand guidelines for parent company Epsilon that revamped its identity and ensured visual consistency with Conversant.
- Mentored a team of local and remote art directors, simultaneously implementing Workfront, a newly-adopted project management tool.

#### JACK IN THE BOX SAN DIEGO, CA

# Creative Services Manager, 05/2014-06/2017

 Oversaw all work produced by the internal creative team, ensuring it met brand standards and arrived on-schedule to over 2,000 restaurants.

## **AECOM SAN DIEGO. CA**

## Graphic Designer, 06/2011-05/2014

 Provided comprehensive design services to AECOM's entire Southern California region, prioritizing efficiency and attention to detail.

## UPSHOT CHICAGO, IL

#### Art Director, 04/2007-04/2011

 Generated artwork, from concept to execution, for over 20 national marketing campaigns, including many for Kraft Foods and MillerCoors.

# **EDUCATION**

#### GENERAL ASSEMBLY CHICAGO. IL

Software Engineering Intensive, 2021

#### THE ILLINOIS INSTITUTE OF ART CHICAGO. IL

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Visual Communication, 2006